Have you ever heard the one about how breastfeeding is free?
هل سمعتم ما يُقال عن أن الرضاعة الطبيعية مجانية؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Yeah, it's pretty funny,
نعم، ذلك مضحك للغاية،
because it's only free if we don't value women's time and energy.
فهي مجانية فقط حين نتجاهل وقت المرأة وطاقتها المبذولة.
Any mother can tell you how much time and energy it takes
تستطيع كل أم إخبارك بالمدة وكمية الطاقة
to liquify her body --
التي يتطلبها منها عصر جسمها --
to literally dissolve herself --
أن تقوم بتحليل جسمها حرفيًا --
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
as she feeds this precious little cannibal.
بينما تقوم بإرضاع هذا المفترس الصغير الغالي.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Milk is why mammals suck.
ترضع الثدييات للحصول على الحليب.
At Arizona State University,
في جامعة ولاية أريزونا،
in the Comparative Lactation Lab,
في مختبر الرضاعة المقارنة،
I decode mothers' milk composition
أقوم بتحليل مكونات حليب الأم
to understand its complexity
حتى أفهم تعقيداته
and how it influences infant development.
والطريقة التي يؤثر من خلالها على تطور الرضيع.
The most important thing that I've learned
وأهم ما تعلمته
is that we do not do enough to support mothers and babies.
هو أننا لا نقوم بما فيه الكفاية لدعم الأمهات والأطفال الرضع.
And when we fail mothers and babies,
وعندما نتخلّف عن واجبنا تجاه الأمهات والأطفال،
we fail everyone who loves mothers and babies:
فإننا نخيِّب آمال جميع من يحبون الأمهات والأطفال:
the fathers, the partners, the grandparents, the aunties,
الآباء، الأزواج، الأجداد، العمّات،
the friends and kin that make our human social networks.
الأصدقاء والأقارب الذين يشكِّلون شبكاتنا الاجتماعية البشرية.
It's time that we abandon simple solutions and simple slogans,
حان الوقت لنتخلى عن الحلول البسيطة والشعارات الجوفاء،
and grapple with the nuance.
والتعامل بجدية مع الفروقات الدقيقة.
I was very fortunate
لقد حالفني الحظ
to run smack-dab into that nuance very early,
بالاصطدام بتلك الفروقات في وقت مبكر جدًا،
during my first interview with a journalist
خلال أول مقابلة لي مع صحفية
when she asked me,
حين سألتني:
"How long should a mother breastfeed her baby?"
"إلى متى يجب على الأم إرضاع طفلها؟"
And it was that word "should" that brought me up short,
استوقفتني كلمة "يجب" قليلًا،
because I will never tell a woman what she should do with her body.
حيث أنني لن أخبر أي امرأة أبدًا بما يجب عليها أن تفعل بجسمها.
Babies survive and thrive
يعيش الأطفال ويكبرون
because their mother's milk is food, medicine and signal.
لأن حليب أمهاتهم غذاء ودواء وإشارة.
For young infants,
بالنسبة للأطفال الرضع،
mother's milk is a complete diet
فإن حليب الأم هو وجبة غذائية متكاملة
that provides all the building blocks for their bodies,
توفر لأجسامهم كل مقوِّمات البناء والنمو،
that shapes their brain
التي تشكِّل أدمغتهم
and fuels all of their activity.
وتمنحهم الطاقة اللازمة لجميع أنشطتهم.
Mother's milk also feeds the microbes
يعمل حليب الأم أيضًا على تغذية الميكروبات
that are colonizing the infant's intestinal tract.
التي تعيش في القناة الهضمية للرضيع.
Mothers aren't just eating for two,
لا تأكل الأمهات لشخصين فقط،
they're eating for two to the trillions.
إنهن يأكلن لاثنين مقابل ترليونات.
Milk provides immunofactors that help fight pathogens
يوفر الحليب عوامل مناعية تساهم في محاربة مسبِّبات الأمراض،
and mother's milk provides hormones that signal to the infant's body.
كما يوفر حليب الأم هرمونات ترسل إشارات إلى جسم الرضيع.
But in recent decades,
ولكننا في العقود الأخيرة
we have come to take milk for granted.
أصبحنا نعتبر الحليب شيئًا عاديًا.
We stopped seeing something in plain sight.
لم نعد نرى بعض الأشياء بوضوح.
We began to think of milk as standardized, homogenized, pasteurized,
بدأنا نعتبر الحليب كشيء معياري، ومتجانس، ومبستر،
packaged, powdered, flavored and formulated.
ومعلّب، ومسحوق، ذي نكهة ومُعالج.
We abandoned the milk of human kindness
تركنا الحليب الممزوج بالحب البشري
and turned our priorities elsewhere.
وجعلنا الأولوية لأشياء أخرى.
At the National Institutes of Health
في معاهد الصحة الوطنية
in Washington DC
في واشنطن العاصمة
is the National Library of Medicine,
توجد المكتبة الوطنية لعلم الطب،
which contains 25 million articles --
التي تضم 25 مليون مقالًا
the brain trust of life science and biomedical research.
تشكِّل خلاصة علم الحياة والأبحاث الطبية البيولوجية.
We can use keywords to search that database,
يمكننا استخدام كلمات مفتاحية للبحث في قاعدة البيانات تلك،
and when we do that,
وعندما نفعل ذلك،
we discover nearly a million articles about pregnancy,
نكتشف نحو مليون مقال حول الحمل،
but far fewer about breast milk and lactation.
وأقل بكثير عن حليب الأم والإرضاع.
When we zoom in on the number of articles just investigating breast milk,
وعندما ندقق النظر في عدد المقالات التي تبحث فقط في حليب الأم،
we see that we know much more about coffee, wine and tomatoes.
نجد أننا نعلم أكثر بكثير عن القهوة والنبيذ والطماطم.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
We know over twice as much about erectile dysfunction.
نعلم بمقدار الضِّعف عن الضعف الجنسي.
I'm not saying we shouldn't know about those things --
لا أقول بأنه لا يتوجب علينا المعرفة بهذه الأمور --
I'm a scientist, I think we should know about everything.
أنا عالمة، أعتقد بأنه علينا المعرفة بكل شيء.
But that we know so much less --
لكن أن نعرف أقل بكثير --
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
about breast milk --
عن حليب الأم،
the first fluid a young mammal is adapted to consume --
وهو السائل الأول الذي يتأقلم الثديي الصغير على تناوله،
should make us angry.
يجب أن يُشعرنا بالغضب.
Globally, nine out of 10 women will have at least one child in her lifetime.
عالميًّا، تسع من كل عشر نساء سيُنجبن طفلًا واحدًا على الأقل في حياتهن.
That means that nearly 130 million babies are born each year.
وهذا يعني أن قرابة 130 مليون طفل يولدون في كل عام.
These mothers and babies deserve our best science.
هؤلاء الأمهات والأطفال يستحقون منا قدرًا أكبر من المعرفة بشؤونهم.
Recent research has shown that milk doesn't just grow the body,
لقد أظهرت الأبحاث الأخيرة بأن الحليب لا يساعد الجسم على النمو فحسب،
it fuels behavior and shapes neurodevelopment.
بل يؤثر أيضاً على السلوك وآلية تطور الجهاز العصبي.
In 2015, researchers discovered
في عام 2015، اكتشف الباحثون
that the mixture of breast milk and baby saliva --
بأن مزج حليب الأم مع لعاب الطفل،
specifically, baby saliva --
خصوصًا لعاب الطفل،
causes a chemical reaction that produces hydrogen peroxide
يسبِّب تفاعلًا كيميائيًّا ينتج عنه بيروكسيد الهيدروجين
that can kill staph and salmonella.
الذي يستطيع القضاء على البكتيريا العنقودية والسالمونيلا.
And from humans and other mammal species,
ومن البشر والثدييات الأخرى،
we're starting to understand that the biological recipe of milk
بدأنا نفهم بأن وجبة الحليب البيولوجية
can be different when produced for sons or daughters.
يمكن أن تكون مختلفة عند إنتاجها للأبناء أو البنات.
When we reach for donor milk in the neonatal intensive care unit,
عندما نلجأ إلى الحليب المُتبرَّع به في وحدة الرعاية المكثفة لحديثي الولادة،
or formula on the store shelf,
أو غذاء بديل على رف المتجر،
it's nearly one-size-fits-all.
فهو يمثل تقريبًا وجبة واحدة مناسبة للجميع.
We aren't thinking about how sons and daughters may grow at different rates,
نحن لا نضع في الحسبان ما قد يتعلق بنمو الأبناء والبنات على معدلات مختلفة،
or different ways,
أو بطرق مختلفة،
and that milk may be a part of that.
وبأن الحليب قد يكون له دور في ذلك.
Mothers have gotten the message
استوعبت الأمهات الرسالة،
and the vast majority of mothers intend to breastfeed,
وتتجه الأغلبية الساحقة من الأمهات إلى الإرضاع،
but many do not reach their breastfeeding goals.
ولكن الكثير منهن لا يحققن أهدافهن من الرضاعة الطبيعية.
That is not their failure;
هذا ليس فشلًا يترتب عليهن؛
it's ours.
إنه فشلنا.
Increasingly common medical conditions like obesity, endocrine disorders,
الحالات الطبية الشائعة على نحو متزايد، مثل السمنة واضطرابات الغدد الصماء
C-section and preterm births
وحالات الولادة القيصرية والمبكرة،
all can disrupt the underlying biology of lactation.
كلها من شأنها أن تهدد الأساس البيولوجي للإرضاع.
And many women do not have knowledgeable clinical support.
ولا يتوفر لدى الكثير من النساء دعم طبي خبير.
Twenty-five years ago,
قبل خمسة وعشرين عامًا،
the World Health Organization and UNICEF established criteria
وضعت منظمة الصحة العالمية بالتعاون مع اليونيسيف
for hospitals to be considered baby friendly --
معايير خاصة للمستشفيات كي يتم اعتبارها ملائمة للأطفال،
that provide the optimal level of support for mother-infant bonding
وهي توفر أعلى مستويات الدعم للأمومة
and infant feeding.
وتغذية الطفل الرضيع.
Today, only one in five babies in the United States
واليوم، واحد فقط من كل خمسة أطفال في الولايات المتحدة
is born in a baby-friendly hospital.
يُولد في مستشفى ملائم للأطفال.
This is a problem,
هذه مشكلة،
because mothers can grapple with many problems
حيث قد تواجه الأمهات العديد من المشاكل
in the minutes, hours, days and weeks of lactation.
خلال دقائق وساعات وأيام وأسابيع الإرضاع.
They can have struggles with establishing latch,
قد تواجه الأمهات صعوبات تتعلق بالتقاط الرضيع للثدي،
with pain,
والألم،
with milk letdown
وإدرار الحليب،
and perceptions of milk supply.
ومفاهيم الإمداد بالحليب.
These mothers deserve knowledgeable clinical staff
تستحق هذه الأمهات توفر طاقم طبي ذي خبرة
that understand these processes.
يفهم هذه العمليات.
Mothers will call me as they're grappling with these struggles,
ستتصل بي الأمهات عند مواجهة هذه الصعوبات،
crying with wobbly voices.
وهن يجهشن بالبكاء.
"It's not working.
"هذا لا يُجدي.
This is what I'm supposed to naturally be able to do.
هذا هو ما يُفترض بي فعله بشكل طبيعي.
Why is it not working?"
لماذا لا يُجدي هذا الأمر؟"
And just because something is evolutionarily ancient
وفقط لأن شيئًا ما تطوري قديم
doesn't mean that it's easy or that we're instantly good at it.
فهذا لا يعني أنه سهل أو بأننا نجيد القيام به فورًا.
You know what else is evolutionarily ancient?
أتعلمون ما هو الأمر الآخر التطوري القديم؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Sex.
الجنس.
And nobody expects us to start out being good at it.
لا أحد يتوقع منا البدء في ذلك على نحو جيد.
(Laughter)
(َضحك)
Clinicians best deliver quality equitable care
يقدِّم الأطباء أفضل رعاية بجودة منصفة
when they have continuing education
عند حصولهم على التعليم المستمر
about how to best support lactation and breastfeeding.
حول أفضل الطرق لتعزيز الإرضاع والرضاعة الطبيعية.
And in order to have that continuing education,
ومن أجل الحصول على ذلك التعليم المستمر،
we need to anchor it to cutting-edge research
علينا دعمه بأبحاث حديثة
in both the life sciences and the social sciences,
في علوم الحياة والعلوم الاجتماعية على حد سواء،
because we need to recognize
لأن علينا الاعتراف
that too often
بأنه في كثير من الأحيان
historical traumas and implicit biases
تقف الصدمات التاريخية والتحيّز الضمني
sit in the space between a new mother and her clinician.
حائلًا بين الأم الجديدة وطبيبها.
The body is political.
الجسم سياسي.
If our breastfeeding support is not intersectional,
إن لم يكن دعم الإرضاع لدينا متعدد الجوانب،
it's not good enough.
فإنه ليس جيدًا بما فيه الكفاية.
And for moms who have to return for work,
أما بالنسبة للأمهات الملزمات بالعودة إلى العمل،
because countries like the United States do not provide paid parental leave,
لأن دولًا مثل الولايات المتحدة لا توفر إجازة أمومة مدفوعة الأجر،
they can have to go back in as short as just a few days after giving birth.
يترتب عليهن العودة إلى العمل خلال أيام قليلة بعد الولادة.
How do we optimize mother and infant health
كيف نحسِّن من مستوى صحة الأم والرضيع
just by messaging about breast milk to moms
فقط من خلال توعية الأمهات حول حليب الأم
without providing the institutional support
دون تقديم الدعم المؤسساتي
that facilitates that mother-infant bonding
الذي ييسِّر تكوين تلك العلاقة بين الأم والرضيع
to support breastfeeding?
لتعزيز الرضاعة الطبيعية؟
The answer is: we can't.
الإجابة هي بأننا لا نستطيع.
I'm talking to you, legislators,
إنني أتحدث إليكم، أيها المشرِّعون،
and the voters who elect them.
والناخبون الذين ينتخبونهم.
I'm talking to you, job creators and collective bargaining units,
إنني أتحدث إليكم، يا مستحدثي الأعمال ووحدات التفاوض الجماعي،
and workers, and shareholders.
والعمال، وأصحاب الأسهم.
We all have a stake in the public health of our community,
كلنا لدينا مصلحة في الصحة العامة لمجتمعنا،
and we all have a role to play in achieving it.
وكلنا لدينا دور نقوم به تجاه تحقيق ذلك.
Breast milk is a part of improving human health.
حليب الأم هو جزء من تعزيز صحة الإنسان.
In the NICU, when infants are born early or sick or injured,
في وحدات العناية المكثفة بحديثي الولادة،
milk or bioactive constituents in milk can be critically important.
يمكن للحليب أو مكوناته الحيوية النشطة أن تكون مهمة للغاية.
Environments or ecologies,
أما في حالة البيئات أو الإيكولوجيا
or communities where there's high risk of infectious disease,
أو المجتمعات التي يزداد فيها خطر الإصابة بالأمراض المعدية،
breast milk can be incredibly protective.
يمكن لحليب الأم أن يكون عنصر وقاية مدهش.
Where there are emergencies like storms and earthquakes,
وفي الأماكن التي تشهد حدوث كوارث مثل الأعاصير والزلازل،
when the electricity goes out,
وعند انقطاع الكهرباء،
when safe water is not available,
وعند عدم توفر مياه صالحة للشرب،
breast milk can keep babies fed and hydrated.
يمكن لحليب الأم أن يمدّ الأطفال بالغذاء والماء باستمرار.
And in the context of humanitarian crises,
وفي حالات الأزمات الإنسانية،
like Syrian mothers fleeing war zones,
كالأمهات السوريات الهاربات من مناطق الحرب،
the smallest drops can buffer babies from the biggest global challenges.
فإن القليل منه يمكن أن يحمي الأطفال من أعظم التحديات العالمية.
But understanding breast milk is not just about messaging to mothers
ولكن فهم حليب الأم لا يقتصر فقط على توعية الأمهات
and policy makers.
وواضعي السياسات.
It's also about understanding what is important in breast milk
إنه أيضًا عن فهم ما هو مهم في حليب الأم
so that we can deliver better formulas
حتى نتمكن من تقديم بدائل أفضل
to moms who cannot or do not breastfeed for whatever reason.
للأمهات اللواتي يعجزن عن الإرضاع لأي سبب كان.
We can all do a better job
نستطيع جميعًا أن نقدِّم ما هو أفضل
of supporting the diversity of moms raising their babies
من ناحية دعم مختلف الأمهات اللواتي يربين أطفالهن
in a diversity of ways.
بطرق مختلفة.
As women around the world struggle
وبينما تكافح النساء حول العالم
to achieve political, social and economic equality,
لتحقيق المساواة السياسية والاجتماعية والاقتصادية،
we must reimagine motherhood
يتوجب علينا إعادة النظر في الأمومة
as not the central, core aspect of womanhood,
ليس كجانب مركزي وجوهري للأنوثة،
but one of the many potential facets of what makes women awesome.
بل كأحد الجوانب الكثيرة الكامنة التي تجعل النساء رائعات.
It's time.
حان الوقت لذلك.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)